We've been hearing this unrelenting discourse
Invariablemente en São Paulo estamos viendo a ese discurso:
about the creation of cultural centers here in Sao Paulo, which
creación de centros culturales, que en realidad quieren imponer un concepto de cultura
is actually a way of imposing another concept of culture
imponer una narrativa dominante
to wipe off stories that are not interesting, profitable
para borrar historias y narrativas
or valuable to the real estate market.
que no interesan al lucro no interesan a la valoración territorial.
And this is what's happening here at Vila Itororó.
Y aquí en la villa es eso que está sucediendo
This is the dirty trick. Everything I'm telling you now
Y esa que es la trampa de la historia
could be information to be presented at the cultural center,
Todo eso que estoy narrando aquí puede ser puesto adentro del centro cultural
like a good testimonial.
como un óptimo depoimiento.
And yet they say, "look how democratic and open to new
Y el centro cultural va a decir: Mira como somos democráticos.
stories we are. This is the real story,
Mira como somos abiertos a las narrativas múltiples
our cultural center is different.
Esa es la historia, pero nuestro centro cultural es diferente.
We present all the perspectives of the story,
Nosotros mostramos todos los lados.
We want to keep everyone's memories alive."
Nosotros queremos mantener la memoria viva.
But what's really hidden behind that discourse
Y qué está escondido en ese discurso sórdido?
is that this place will no longer be a place of housing.
Que aquí no va a ser más vivienda.